In the last lecture we created the individual build control component.
Son derste bireysel cvata kontrol bileenini yarattk.
Now we want to output a couple of build controls
imdi iki kontroln bir iftini kartmak istiyoruz.
and for that, I will create a constant, not the state, not a property just another constant in this file
Ve bunun iin bir sabit oluturacam, devlet deil, bu dosyada sadece say sabiti olan bir
but one which I won't export which i'll name controls.
mlk deil, kontrol isimlendiren, vermeyeceim bir devlet.
And this is optional, you could just hard code all the controls but I want to have an array for which
Ve bu yalnzca tm denetimleri zor kod istee baldr ancak rahata tm
I can loop to conveniently build all these build controls and render them. So here I want to have a couple of
bu yerleik denetimler oluturmak ve bunlar bylece bir ift javascript nesneleri her biri salata gibi bir etiket
javascript objects, each should have a label like salad and then a type, also salad but with a lowercase
olmaldr ilemek iin dng iin bir dizi olmasn istiyorsanz ve daha sonra bir tr veya bir salata ama kk
s and this is just one possible approach.
bir s ile ve sadece olas bir yaklam.
Now I will replicate this for all the ingredients I know I know in this app I mean, bacon for example
imdi bunu bildiim tm maddeler iin tekrarlayacam biliyorum Bu uygulamada biliyorum pastrma, rnein
cheese and the types by the way should meet the types you're checking for in the burger ingredient component
onun iin Ve bu arada bu trler l gei aamasnda burger bileen bileeninde kontrol ettiiniz trleri karlamal
in that switch statement, you should have the same casing and so on
ve siz de ayn muhafaza ve benzerleri.
as here, in the type property.
Ve burada Type zellii.
Now we get an array of controls and again this was just added for convenience,
imdi bir dizi kontrol saladk ve yine bu rahatlk salamak iin eklendi.
I now want to use it here in my build control component.
Ve fatura kontrol bileenimde kullanmak istiyorum.
First of all I will use the build controls css class so I will quickly add import to that classes
Her eyden nce kaburga kontrolleri siestas snfn kullanacam, bu yzden
from ./buildControls css and assign this to the wrapping
CSX kontrolleri altndaki bor snflarna bir liman ekleyip paketlemeye atayacam.
div here, build excuse me, classes.BuildControls, like this.
Savunmak yerleik mazeretler bana byle kontroller kurmak.
And now inside of that div, I want to loop through all the controls and render a build control for each
Ve imdi div'n iinde tm denetimleri tekrarlamak ve her biri iin bir cvata
of them.
kontrol yaratmak istiyorum.
So let's first import the build control singular component
Bu yzden, nce ithalat yaptklar ikisi de tekil bileenleri kontrol ediyor.
we created in the last lecture. We can find in the build control folder and there it's the build control
Son dersin sonunda, cvata kontrol klasrnde bulabiliriz ve cvata
javascript file.
kontrol javascript dosyas var.
Now let's create a loop with curly braces to inline it here because it's really short, take that controls
imdi buraya yerletirmek iin Cauley parantezleri ile bir tuvalet yaratalm, nk burada gerekten eriemediimiz bu dosyann
constant which is part of this file in which we therefore can access here
bir paras olan l Kontroller Konseptini alyoruz.
because always keep in mind you're in javascript here,
nk her zaman burada javascript bulunduunu unutmayn.
of course you can access other stuff from this file.
Tabii ki dosyamzdan bu dosyadan eriebilirsiniz.
So access controls, call map there and now map each control, so each element of this array into a build
Dolaysyla, eriim denetimleri haritay orada arar ve her denetimi bu dizinin her bir esini yerleik bir denetime yerletirirsiniz.
control, a self-closing tag, where you set a key that's required. The key can't just be the label because
Bylece, anahtar bulmak iin gereken anahtar ayarladnz kendiliinden kapanan bir etiketi, benzersiz bir tanmlayc olduundan
that is a unique identifier,
yalnzca etiket olamaz.
we never have a label more than once, and then also pass label to this build control component.
Hibir zaman bir kereden fazla bir etiketimiz olmad ve daha sonra tm gei etiketi kontrol bileeni oluturuyor.
Now the type will become important later,
imdi tr sonradan nemli hale gelecektir.
for now let's see if we can see something.
imdilik, bir eyler grebilir miyiz greceiz.
So make sure you save all the files and now that we export build controls,
Bu yzden tm dosyalar kaydettiinizden emin olun ve imdi de iki denetimi veriyoruz.
let's go to the burger builder and insert it here
Burger kurucusuna gidelim ve buraya takn.
instead of this placeholder.
Bu yer tutucunun yerine.
So let's add import here at the top, buildControls from
O halde buradan st cvata kontrollerine bir liman ekleyelim.
and now we need to go into the components folder, into the burger folder, the build controls folder and
Ve imdi components klasrne built controls klasr olan Bergere klasrne gitmeliyiz ve
pick the buildControls javascript file and now simply output it here in place of that div, build controls
cvata kontrolleri javascript dosyasn setik ve imdi cesur bir yap kendi kapan esini kontrol eden yerinde
a self-closing element.
bir yl kt.
Now if you save that and make sure all files are saved, you should see these build controls below the burger
denetimleri burgerin altnda grmeniz gerekir ve DS her iki denetimi de henz bir ey yapmaz.
and these build controls won't do anything just yet
imdi, tm dosyalarn kaydedildiinden emin olmak iin bu cesur
but we're really close to hooking up these buttons and hence editing this burger.
Ancak biz gerekten bu dmeleri balamaya ve dolaysyla bu burgeri dzenleme konusunda ok yaknz.